mumsnet.com 2019-12-30

# Privacy policy | Mumsnet

This policy explains the way that we collect, use and protect your data as well as your choices with regard to your data.

We’ve tried to be as clear as we can be and to avoid unnecessary jargon, while including all the relevant information – but please do [contactus@mumsnet.com](mailto:contactus@mumsnet.com) if anything doesn’t make sense or needs expanding on. Because, by necessity, this is a long document and because we’re all pressed for time, we've summarised the key points – you can click on each one to get more detailed information. Please do read the whole thing if you can

######  Our aims and duty of care 

\+ 

We recognise our duty of care with regards to your data and will always endeavour to do the right thing with the personal data you choose to share with us, including: not compromising your anonymity; protecting your privacy; storing your data securely and giving you control over your own data.

Our mission at Mumsnet is to help make parents’ lives easier. We believe that securing your data, preserving your anonymity, protecting your privacy, and giving you control over your data are an important aspect of that mission.

We believe that employing data and data analytics appropriately can improve the user experience on Mumsnet. Data you give us when filling in forms (when joining, for example or when using the site or our apps) helps us show you more relevant things. It also allows us to see which aspects of the site are popular and well-used, meaning we can improve Mumsnet for everyone.

See more + 

######  Your data - what we store and why 

\+ 

We store IP address, cookies, your device’s unique ID, page browsing history, ads you’ve viewed and clicked, searches you’ve made on site, approximate location, and any enquiries you’ve made. For registered members we also store username, password and email address; discussions you may have with Mumsnet site moderators; and a summary of decisions we’ve taken about you if we’ve reviewed your use of Mumsnet Talk for any reason. Registered members may also have given us more data on sign up, such as the age of their children.

We store your email address to register you and contact you (if you have asked for email newsletters) and we store things such as IP address, cookies and device ID so that our systems recognise you if you return to Mumsnet. We store things such as your device’s reading habits to show you things we think may be of interest to you (eg content or ads). When we look at this information across large numbers of users, it helps us see which parts of Mumsnet are well-used and which aren’t, and this helps us to decide what sort of content and features might be useful to develop. Subject to the permissions you have given us (as described in your permissions and choices below), we may also pass your device's reading habits to selected brands for these brands to show you things they think may be of interest to you (eg content or ads).

We don’t require your name or address when you view Mumsnet content or register with the site, and you can use Mumsnet fully without providing it.

Subject to your permissions and choices, we collect, store and process the data listed in this section. We believe we provide a useful service, and therefore have a legitimate interest in processing your data which benefits both Mumsnet and you as a Mumsnet user.

**We store the following data for all users, whether registered or not:**

  * IP address, cookies, device ID – to identify your web browser and device.
  * Page browsing information – to enable us to show you more relevant things and to understand how people use Mumsnet, so we can improve it.
  * Within our user database, we assign your internet browser and device a unique “Mumsnet Identity Number”. Against this identity number we record the topic of the content that your device is viewing or creating – in other words, your device’s “reading habits”. This helps us understand what you may be interested in so that we can show you things we think may be relevant to you (such as ads or other Mumsnet content). When we look at this information from all users, we can see what is popular and less popular, helping us to develop Mumsnet over time.
  * We also use Google Analytics to report on page views in aggregate to help us understand usage trends. We do not pass your personal data to Google and your IP address is anonymised before we share this information with Google Analytics. Google uses cookies and can learn about your browsing on Mumsnet to inform Google ads and other Google services, as explained here: <https://policies.google.com/privacy/partners>
  * Ads viewed and clicked and searches you’ve made on site – to show you more relevant ads and content in future.
  * Enquiries you make – we sometimes give you the option of using Mumsnet to enquire about a product or service (such as getting a quote to repair your boiler). This is optional and we only give users this option if we trust the company and think the service might be helpful to you. We will always explicitly ask for your permission before recording or passing this information to that company or to anyone else.

**We store the following information for registered members:**

  * Username, password, email address – so that you can log in. If you choose to join Mumsnet we ask for your email address so that we can create an account for you and check you’re a real person (to prevent ‘bots’ signing up). We won’t send you newsletters or mass email communications that you haven’t asked for, and we don’t sell your email address to anyone else.
  * Discussions that take place over email or via Private Messages between you and Mumsnet moderators – so that we have a record.
  * A summary of any actions we may have taken with regard to your use of Mumsnet Talk (usually in response to reported posts) – so that we have a record and can moderate fairly.

**We also store the following optional data for registered members:**

  * Registration data: facts about you that you choose to provide in the sign-up process, such as your date of birth, gender, whether you are pregnant, whether you have children, their ages and genders, and which email newsletters from us you would like to receive. If you give us this data it helps us to show you more relevant things (for example, sending you emails about pregnancy if you have asked for them). We do not share this information with anyone else. Provision of this data is optional; you can skip this stage.
  * Permissions to email you, to send you newsletters that you have chosen to receive from Mumsnet.
  * Private Messages that you choose to send other users.
  * Data that you provide when taking part in surveys, panels, product tests, quizzes or competitions. For these things, we sometimes ask for your name and address (for example to send you a product to test) or other data requested by the competition provider (such as your email address). Before recording or passing this information to another organisation, we will provide the organisation’s data policy and clearly ask for your permission each time.

See more + 

######  Posting on Mumsnet Talk 

\+ 

Of your registration data, only your Mumsnet username is displayed on screen for other Mumsnet users to see – but posts on Mumsnet Talk are visible to anyone on the internet. So when posting, you should bear in mind that any personally identifying details you include in the text or pictures you post could be seen by anyone.

We also provide an anonymised copy of all Talk posts to a handful of carefully chosen organisations so that they can analyse social trends. None of your personal information is ever shared and we remove Mumsnet usernames before sharing this information.

Registered members of Mumsnet can start discussions and add comments, pictures and videos to existing discussions within Mumsnet Talk’s forums under Mumsnet’s Terms of Use. This is optional in the sense that it’s up to you whether you post on Mumsnet or not; if you do post we always store the contents of those posts. These posts are public, but of your registration data, only your Mumsnet username is displayed on screen. Your Mumsnet username is picked by you when you join Mumsnet; you can change it at any time in My Account.

Mumsnet’s forums (with the exception of some topics, like “Off the beaten track”) are visible to search engines. This means that any personal information users choose to share in their posts on Mumsnet can be seen widely. We cannot control who sees these posts. However, wherever appropriate we remind users that Mumsnet’s forums are highly visible and can be read by anyone, anywhere.

In all your posts on Mumsnet Talk, in personal messages to other users, and in choosing your username, you should be mindful about the possibility that information you choose to disclose could lead to someone working out who you are in ‘real life’. For example, anything that references your real life name, your children’s real names, where you live or your date of birth could make it easy for someone to work out who you are. Other personal information in your posts – how many children you have, what job you do, that you work from home on Thursdays, that your spouse is a mountain bike enthusiast – might also allow people reading Mumsnet to work out who you are (through ‘jigsaw identification’).

Mumsnet is a site for grown-ups and we believe that our users are adults who can decide for themselves what information they choose to share on Mumsnet Talk. That said, if you’re ever worried that you’ve said too much, hit ‘report’ on one of your posts and explain the problem to our site moderation team; they will be happy to help if they can.

You should be aware that the moderation team and a small number of other members of staff at Mumsnet have access to your Talk posts and can see that content in combination with your registration data. We restrict to the minimum the number of staff who have access to this data and we constantly review this. You can check your registration data in My Account.

We provide a copy of all Talk posts to a small number of organisations for analysis or to create software analysis tools to analyse brands and sentiment towards topics. Your personal data and username is not included in the copies of posts that we provide to these organisations.

See more + 

######  Your permissions and choices 

\+ 

You can change your registration data and your email preferences on Mumsnet at any time on your My Account page. You can also manage your cookie preferences – click on this section for how to do this, but remember it may affect how well this site works. You can delete your account by going to My Account.

**Your registration data**

You can change the information that you provided when you registered, including your email address and Mumsnet username, on your My Account page.

If you have signed in using Facebook or Google, you can stop access at any time via your Facebook or Google account settings. If you still wish to post on Mumsnet you’ll then need to register a Mumsnet username and password via our Registration page.

**Your email preferences**

You can change which newsletters you receive, or ensure that you do not receive any newsletters from Mumsnet, by going to My Account.

**Your posts**

If you’re ever worried that you’ve said too much, hit ‘report’ on one of your posts and explain the problem to our site Moderation team; they will be happy to help if they can. You can request a retrospective name change – this means that all your previous posts will appear under a different username.

**Your cookies**

Most web browsers automatically accept cookies. A cookie is a small, temporary file which a web server sends to your web browser to be stored. Cookies allow Mumsnet to identify your web browser and device if we see it again.

Cookies do not contain your name or other personal details and there are some benefits to you and Mumsnet:

  * “Information storage and access” cookies allow you to perform certain functions like logging into Mumsnet. Cookies improve your experience of the site. For example, they allow you to log in and post, and allow us to show you discussions you've already read in a different colour, and to display them top-down or bottom-up according to your preference.
  * Cookies also help us to show you more relevant content and ads. These are formally known as “Personalisation” cookies, “Ad selection, delivery, reporting” cookies and “Content selection, delivery, reporting” cookies. As an example: if we know you’ve read our pregnancy content, we can show you pregnancy-related ads from brands that might be particularly relevant to pregnant women. To help keep the site running, we earn money by showing ads to people who might be interested in them – relevant ads are more likely to be clicked on, and command a higher price. The technology companies that Mumsnet allows to place cookies (known as third-party cookies) on your device are listed in the section in this Privacy Policy called “Where your data is stored”. Some of these technology companies deliver advertising and, as well as delivering ads on Mumsnet, may use your cookies to deliver ads to you on other sites (which is called “retargeting”).
  * “Measurement” cookies allow us to gather information about how many people visit Mumsnet, how often, and what they look at while on the site (a process called ‘analytics’). If you visit multiple pages or come back to Mumsnet after a break, cookies mean we do not count you as a new visitor. Using cookies like this allows us to compile aggregate statistics about how many users Mumsnet has and how long people use the site for, on average. We share this anonymous information with advertisers. Understanding what’s well-used on Mumsnet means we can create more of what users find useful and less of what they don’t.

There are 3 ways for you to manage your cookie preferences:

  1. The first time you visit Mumsnet you should see a pop-up along the bottom of the screen. You can choose to accept all cookies, by clicking ‘I Agree’, or you can manage your individual preferences by clicking ‘show purposes’.
  2. At the bottom right hand side of this page (The Privacy Policy) you should see a settings toggle which says ‘Privacy setting’. If you click on this a pop-up should appear at the bottom of the screen. Here you can manage all your individual cookie preferences.
  3. If you are a registered member of Mumsnet you can manage your cookie preferences at any time by clicking on ‘My Mumsnet’ and selecting ‘Settings’. Within your Mumsnet settings you should see a settings toggle which says ‘Privacy setting’. If you click on this a pop-up should appear at the bottom of the screen. Here you can manage all your individual cookie preferences.

**Deleting your Mumsnet Account**

You can delete your account by going to My Account. Your Mumsnet posts won’t be deleted, but there will no longer be any personal information associated with them.

**Data requests**

If you’d like you can ask us to provide details of the personal information we hold about you, under the 2018 EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR). To request this information, please email us at [dataenquiry@mumsnet.com](mailto:dataenquiry@mumsnet.com) or write to Mumsnet Limited, Studios 13-16, Deane House Studios, 27 Greenwood Place, London NW5 1LB.

See more + 

######  How long is your data held 

\+ 

Any personal data you give us, or that we collect when you use Mumsnet, will be retained by us for as long as it’s needed to perform its function. Registration data is held permanently unless you deregister. There’s no one-size-fits-all time limit, but we regularly review the data we hold to ensure it is still necessary.

Any personal data that you give us will be retained by us for as long as it's needed to perform its function.

There's no one-size-fits-all time limit, but to give some examples: data provided by members of our Insight panel for that specific purpose is retained for as long as the user remains a member of the panel. Information provided when entering competitions is held for a maximum of three months. Information you give us when you sign up is stored permanently unless you choose to delete it or unless you delete your Mumsnet account.

Private Messages are stored until you delete them. If you delete your account, your messages will also be deleted.

We regularly review the data held by Mumsnet’s different teams and delete information that is no longer needed. All the data we hold is stored securely and only accessible to authorised staff members, who have regular data training.

See more + 

######  Signing in with Facebook or Google 

\+ 

You can choose to log in to Mumsnet using Facebook or Google. When you do this, Facebook or Google will know you’ve logged in to Mumsnet. By logging in via Facebook or Google you grant us access to your Facebook or Google registered email address. We do not use (and cannot obtain) your Friends list and we do not ask for or receive any data that Facebook holds on you.

If you choose to join Mumsnet you are asked to create a username and password. If you prefer, you can log in using Facebook or Google instead, meaning you don’t have to create and remember another password.

If you log in via Facebook or Google you will grant us access to your Facebook or Google registered email address only. We do not use (and cannot obtain) your Friends list and we do not ask for or receive other Facebook data. By default, the Facebook login process says it requires access to your Public Profile, but we do not store or use that data. However, if you choose this option, Facebook and Google will know that you have logged in to Mumsnet. We do not know whether Facebook or Google use this data (for example to make ads more relevant).

You may stop access at any time via your Facebook or Google account settings. If you want to carry on being able to post on Mumsnet you will then need to register a Mumsnet username and password.

See more + 

######  Where is your data stored 

\+ 

Your data is stored by our web hosting company DSC, and by Amazon Web Services. Unless you have turned cookies off, some data technology companies (such as Google and Lotame) store your cookies; they do not have access to any personal information about you beyond your browsing habits.

Your data is stored by our web server hosting providers: [DSC Limited](https://www.dscga.com/index.php/privacy-policy/), [Amazon Web Services](https://aws.amazon.com/privacy/?nc1=f_pr), and our email service providers: [Campaign Monitor](https://www.campaignmonitor.com/) and [Email Center UK](https://www.emailcenteruk.com/).

The following companies store your cookies on our behalf. We do not share personal data (such as your name or email address) with these companies.

**Tag Management**

Tags are lines of code that run on sites and apps. Mumsnet uses tag management software to run code that connects to third-party technology companies. These third-party technology companies deliver Social Log-In, Advertising and Analytics.

**Social Log-In**

These companies allow you to use your social media account to log in to Mumsnet. This is optional when you [join Mumsnet](http://www.mumsnet.com/register). If you choose to log in via Google or Facebook, those companies will know that you have logged in to Mumsnet.

**Advertising**

The third-party companies below help us to deliver advertising. These companies use cookies to select and deliver advertisements for you, and to measure the delivery and effectiveness of such advertisements. This will include using collected information about your interests in order to select ads for you, processing data about what advertisements were shown, how often they are shown, when and where they are shown, and whether you took any action related to the advertisement, including for example clicking an ad or making a purchase.

These companies deliver advertising on Mumsnet:

**Analytics**

These companies help Mumsnet understand our users:

This company helps Mumsnet understand how our site and apps are performing (for example, reporting on the speed that pages take to load).

See more + 

######  Exceptional circumstances - safeguarding and official investigations 

\+ 

If there are obvious safeguarding reasons, or if we are contacted by the police about a possible breach of the law, we may share your personal information with public authorities without your permission. If we are compelled to do so by a court order, we will share your personal data to the extent specified in the order.

If there are compelling safeguarding considerations, we may share your data with public authorities without your permission. We understand 'compelling safeguarding considerations' to mean credible evidence of imminent risk of serious harm, especially to a child or vulnerable person.

In such circumstances, on the judgement of a senior person within Mumsnet and in consultation with the Data Protection Officer, we may proactively contact relevant authorities (the police or ambulance service, for example) and share any relevant data we have, such as location data, relevant posts, private messages, details of any children who might be at risk, and descriptions of the situation.

If contacted by the police about possible breaches of the law disclosed in posts, we may sometimes – on the judgement of a senior person within Mumsnet and in consultation with the Data Protection Officer – share your personal information with them. We will share your personal information if compelled to do so by a court order, for example under Section 5 of the 2013 Defamation Act.

See more + 

######  Complying with the law and best practice around data 

\+ 

The way we store and process data is compliant with the UK 1998 Data Protection Act, the 2018 EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR), and other relevant pieces of legislation. We always aim to comply both with the spirit as well as the letter of the law and to be responsible with your data.

The way that we store and process data is compliant with the following legislation:

UK Data Protection Act 1988 (DPA)  
EU Data Protection Directive 1995 (DPD)  
EU General Data Protection Regulation 2018 (GDPR)  
ePrivacy Directive 2002 (amended 2009)

As well as keeping up-to-date with laws about data, we aim to take sensible decisions based on common sense, listening to users’ views and industry best practices.

See more + 

######  If our data is compromised 

\+ 

If our security is breached, our data is compromised or if we fail to comply with the law, we will tell affected users as soon as we become aware of the failure. We will report any data breach to the Information Commissioner and, if appropriate, the police, in a timely fashion.

Used appropriately, we strongly believe using data improves the user experience on Mumsnet and supports our aim of making parents’ lives easier. Data you give us when filling in forms on site (when joining, for example) or when you're using the site or our apps helps us show you more relevant things and improve Mumsnet for everyone.

If, via human error, or via a breach of our security, we fail to comply with the law, we will let affected users know as soon as we are aware of it. We will report any data breach to the Information Commissioner in UK and, depending on the circumstances, the Police.

Mumsnet uses best practice, multi-tier web application security for our servers including Denial of Service protection and Web Application Firewall at the network edge. For staff access to all administrative systems, we enforce 2-step verification and IP-based access restrictions. Regular security updates keep Mumsnet staff informed of the latest security threats.

See more + 

######  Alexa Skills 

\+ 

This privacy policy describes how Mumsnet (“Mumsnet”, “us” or “we”) protects your (“you”, “the user”) privacy and your data. Before using any of our Alexa Skills (“our skills”), please read this policy and our Alexa Skills Terms of Use, as well as the [Alexa Terms of Use](https://www.amazon.co.uk/gp/help/customer/display.html?nodeId=201809740) and the [Privacy Policies by the Amazon Digital Services LLC](https://www.amazon.co.uk/gp/help/customer/display.html?nodeId=201909010) (with its affiliates, “Amazon”).

Regarding Amazon, “Alexa” means their Alexa Voice Service which includes third-party services (like our skills) and other related software.

If you use one of our skills you fully agree to this privacy policy.

**General**

When you use our skills you have to talk to Alexa. This voice input is sent to Amazon and us, where we use it to understand what our skill should do for you. This is absolutely necessary for our service to give you an appropriate answer.

**Data**

We only collect personal data necessary to run our skill – this is your due date. We do not share this with anyone outside of Mumsnet.

To improve our services we analyse automatically how often utterances are spoken and other analytics. This is done automatically by Amazon in the Amazon Developer Portal.

For some of our skills, it is necessary to save data for you in our databases. This data is connected to your Alexa-UserId but never to your name or any other personal information. In the case of our “Mumsnet Pregnancy” skill, we save your due date. Otherwise, we would not be able to provide this service.

**Changes**

Our skills or parts of them may change or be updated at any time. Further, this Privacy Policy might change. You can find a link to this policy on the description page of the skill in the Alexa App or in the Alexa Store.

See more + 

######  Updates 

\+ 

Further updates will be noted here as and when they are made.

22 May 2018: deletion policy on Private Messages updated  
8 May 2018: Privacy Policy updated  
17 September 2018: cookie explanations updated to reflect new consent process  
29 August 2019: updates to privacy policy – what data is stored and why  
12 September 2019: Alexa Skills privacy policy included

See more +
